

Leader I Innovator I Strategist

# CONTACT

+1 310.467.4010

michael.lee.1983@icloud.com

stixlee.com

in linkedin.com/in/stix-lee/

# EDUCATION

#### **BACHELOR OF SCIENCE**

United States Military Academy West Point, New York Dean's List

#### **MASTER OF FINE ARTS**

Writers Bootcamp Santa Monica, California

# EXPERTISE

- √ Mobile Leadership
- √ Mobile Strategy
- ✓ Mobile Innovation
- √ iOS Apps & Ecosystems
- ✓ MVVM+
- √ Web 3 for Mobile
- ✓ Decentralized Identity
- ✓ Swift/SwiftUI
- √ Reactive Design
- ✓ Product Management

# Michael "Stix" Lee

# PROFILE

Stix brings long and extensive engineering and leadership experience to mobile systems and iOS app development. Whether creating and delivering great mobile apps, defining and differentiating game-changing mobile products and ecosystems, or simply delivering on complex features, this technical leader specializes in the *delivery* of world-class iOS apps.

"It's not about individual apps. It's about creating a thriving mobile ecosystem" - Stix

# QUALIFICATIONS

# **Proven Technology Leader**

Over 20 years broad technology leadership experience — from defining product and technical vision for multiple iOS applications, to leading individual creative and engineering teams in the delivery of innovative mobile products.

# 15+ Years iOS Experience

Stix has been developing iOS apps for over 15 years. He is a recognized thought leader in iOS and an expert in mobile architectures, mobile ecosystems, and design patterns, and specializes in team leadership, reactive design and advanced language features in Swift & SwiftUI.

# **Principal Mobile Architect & Mobile Thought Leader**

Expert in iOS solutions (Swift), reactive designs (SwiftUI) and creator of the MVVM+ architecture (<a href="https://bit.ly/3S8LF5S">https://bit.ly/3S8LF5S</a>). 10+ years experience leading multi-platform (iOS and Android) mobile teams in the delivery of mobile applications and ecosystems - with well over a dozen past and current Apps deployed to the App Store and Play Store (over 20 million Monthly Active Users).

#### Mobile Strategist & Product Innovator

Strategist and product innovator specializing in product-market fit and rapid monetization across the entire mobile space, including: iOS ecosystems, mobile architectures, full stack Cloud solutions; shared interest networks; anonymous, self-selective demographics (for privacy-enhanced digital advertising); mobile maturity matrix; and a one-page mobile strategy tool for developing and sustaining mobile strategies across an organization.

#### **Expert on Swift & SwiftUI**

Over 9 years experience with Swift (all versions, from Swift 1.2 to current Swift 5.9 - with exclusive focus on Swift development since 2014) and 4+ years experience in SwiftUI (all versions, from SwiftUI v1 to current SwiftUI v5).

#### Thought Leader - Web 3 Solutions for Mobile

Direct hands-on experience applying the entire Web 3 stack to mobile applications, including: Crypto Wallets (single owner & multi-sig); Wallet Connect; Digital Assets (crypto & NFTs); Smart Contracts; approval and signing; decentralized, and self-managed credentials (SSI).

#### **Outstanding Communication Skills**

Published author with proven ability to translate abstract business needs into detailed technical requirements and then communicate product vision and technical direction to customers, partners, executive management and engineering staff.

# Stix Lee

#### √ Leadership

#### √ iOS Architectures

- √ Swift / SwiftUI
- √ Combine
- ✓ MVVM / MVVM+
- √ RESTful APIs
- √ Reactive UX
- √ Real-time Location Tracking
- ✓ Design Patterns
- √ Mobile Ecosystems
- ✓ Universal Deeplinking
- √ SPM / Cocoa Pods
- √ Offline Sync
- √ Objective-C
- √ Crashlytics
- ✓ Push Notifications
- ✓ App Analytics
- √ Git & CI/CD
- √ Machine Learning/Core ML
- √ Content Creation
- ✓ Agile Development
- ✓ Product Management
- ✓ In-app Purchases
- ✓ App Submissions
- ✓ Apple HMI
- √ Crypto Wallets
- √ Identity Wallets
- √ NFTs
- √ Crypto Signing
- √ Polygon
- √ Ethereum

# RECENT EXPERIENCE

# **Principal Mobile Architect**

Blockchains, Inc. (2023 - Present)

Primary solution executive for Blockchains' flagship Web 3 mobile platform. Responsible for mobile solutions (iOS & Android) and product-market fit for: identity, wallet, recovery, and Web 3 discovery. Integration with public blockchains, Know Your Customer (KYC) platforms, Wallet Connect, and other Blockchain mobile apps.

#### Solution Architect & Head of Mobile

Enverus (2019 - 2023)

Led a cross-functional mobile team of 20+ engineers (iOS, Android, and Backend), QA test engineers, and Product Managers. Responsible for the overall solution of three mobile applications (*Intelligence*, *Rigs*, and *S2P*) within a common mobile ecosystem. Principal iOS Engineer (Swift/SwiftUI) on all three mobile platforms.

# iOS/tvOS Specialist / Principal Engineer

Freelance (2017 - 2019)

iOS / tvOS Specialist responsible for the architecture and delivery of critical new features and innovative platforms for multiple clients, with over 2+ million monthly active users (including McDonalds and Spectrum Cable). Key solutions included: DRM, Global Ecosystems, streaming analytics, GDPR, networking & operations, dynamic UX, and app localization.

#### iOS Team Lead

Vixlet (2015 - 2017)

Solution lead for eight Mobile Apps with over 1+ million (aggregate) monthly active users. Head of iOS development (Swift) for innovative, next generation social platforms for Major League Baseball (MLB Fans); L.A. Kings; Liverpool Football Club (LFC Xtra); Men's Tennis (ATP); Slipknot Outside the Nine (OT9), and others.

#### Co-Founder & CTO

Simplexity (2014 - 2015)

Co-Founder, CTO and Product Director for an innovative iOS application that integrated organic, anonymous location tracking with mined social media location data to identify the hottest venues near a users location. One of the first pure-Swift applications deployed to the App Store (October, 2014).

# **Vice President & Industry Executive**

CSC (2004 - 2013)

Executive leader of CSC's Aerospace & Defense business unit for managed application services. Managed a \$100 million annual P&L with 30% or better operating margins and 10% year-over-year growth. Responsible for mobile and enterprise application development and led a global delivery team of 1,000+ engineers, architects, subject matter experts and other specialists.

#### **Co-Founder & Managing Partner**

Kuvera (1998 - 2003)

Responsible for building organizational capabilities, developing innovative service offerings, and led service delivery for critical clients.